<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Root>
	<!--Generic-->
	<Entry>
		<zType/>
		<English/>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_1</zType>
		<English>Units in a Forest get a defensive bonus against link(UNITTRAIT_RANGED) Attacks.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_2</zType>
		<English>Units on Flat terrain are vulnerable to attacks from link(UNITTRAIT_MOUNTED) Units.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_3</zType>
		<English>link(UNITTRAIT_MELEE) link(UNITTRAIT_INFANTRY) can Fortify, gaining a defensive bonus while they remain on their current tile.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_4</zType>
		<English>Land Units can move quickly across water that your Cities and Anchored Boats control.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_5</zType>
		<English>Press [V] to see your link(CONCEPT_TRADE_NETWORK) and Connections.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_6</zType>
		<English>link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING) stockpiles are capped at int(MAX_TRAINING). Above this value, they'll be converted to link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_7</zType>
		<English>You can only use 3 of your Nation's 4 Families each game. Experiment to find out which combinations work best!</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_8</zType>
		<English>Unused link(YIELD_CIVICS)icon(YIELD_CIVICS) and link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING) in your Cities are added to your Nation's stockpile.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_9</zType>
		<English>If you don't want to use all of your link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS), you can end your turn by pressing '6'.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_10</zType>
		<English>Your workers can chop wood from nearby trees. The trees will regrow in several years if they aren't completely removed!</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_11</zType>
		<English>If you don't have enough materials to start a Unit or Improvement, [ALT+Click] to automatically buy what you're missing (assuming you have enough link(YIELD_MONEY)icon(YIELD_MONEY).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_12</zType>
		<English>Building an Improvement on a Hill will increase the time it takes to finish by a year.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_13</zType>
		<English>link(TRIBE_BARBARIANS) are xenophobic tribes hostile to all nations. There are no diplomatic consequences for attacking their units or taking over their land. They have no allies, not even other link(TRIBE_BARBARIANS).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_14</zType>
		<English>If your territory has scant supplies of link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD), consider training military units that rely on link(YIELD_STONE)icon(YIELD_STONE) or link(YIELD_IRON)icon(YIELD_IRON). Concentrate your limited link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD) supply on building Rural tile improvements.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_15</zType>
		<English>link(IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY,2) built next to Mountains produce more link(YIELD_STONE)icon(YIELD_STONE) for each adjacent Mountain tile. link(IMPROVEMENT_QUARRY,2) gain a minor increase when they are built in Arid terrain.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_16</zType>
		<English>link(IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL,2) built adjacent to link(IMPROVEMENT_CAMP,2) gain increased link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD) output; The hunters control predators, forge trails through the forest, etc</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_17</zType>
		<English>Being at war against several opponents can leave your armies overwhelmed, unable to execute enough link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS) to fight effectively on every front. Use diplomacy to avoid this fate.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_18</zType>
		<English>Researching your way to the link(IMPROVEMENT_LUMBERMILL) Improvement takes time. You may need to send link(UNIT_WORKER,2) to forests and thickets outside your borders, to Chop link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD) from link(VEGETATION_TREES) and link(VEGETATION_SCRUB).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_19</zType>
		<English>Expect demand for link(YIELD_FOOD)icon(YIELD_FOOD) to rise as your cities grow and mature.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_20</zType>
		<English>Upgrading units to more advanced technology is materially expensive, but it can rapidly increase your military might.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_21</zType>
		<English>Roads help units move farther with each icon(YIELD_ORDERS)link(YIELD_ORDERS,1) spent, especially when the link(CONCEPT_ROAD) passes through difficult terrain.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_22</zType>
		<English>link(UNITTRAIT_RANGED) units gain an extra tile of link(IMPROVEMENT_RANGE) if positioned on Hills, unless their target is also on Hills.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_23</zType>
		<English>Stationing a military unit on a conquered city site marks the territory as yours. Failing to guard the site may result in it being claimed by a new Barbarian link(CONCEPT_SETTLEMENT) or settled by your rivals.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_24</zType>
		<English>Growing your number of link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS) should be a priority. The more territory and units that you control, the more link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS) your Nation will need to function and to defend itself.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_25</zType>
		<English>The power of each Law tends to increase, the more that your Nation grows. When choosing research, do not neglect unlocking new Laws.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_26</zType>
		<English>A city may build ships if it controls water tiles labeled as Coast.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_27</zType>
		<English>link(UNIT_SCOUT,2) can keep an eye on a large number of tiles. They can provide valuable intelligence regarding enemy strength and movements.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_28</zType>
		<English>Cities with high link(YIELD_GROWTH)icon(YIELD_GROWTH) train new link(UNIT_SETTLER,2), link(UNIT_WORKER,2), and link(UNIT_SCOUT,2) more rapidly.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_29</zType>
		<English>The rate at which military units are produced by a city is tied directly to its link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING) output.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_30</zType>
		<English>The rate at which Projects are completed at a city depends on its link(YIELD_CIVICS)icon(YIELD_CIVICS) output.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_31</zType>
		<English>link(CONCEPT_URBAN) specialists can be upgraded multiple times, greatly increasing the output of an link(CONCEPT_URBAN) building.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_32</zType>
		<English>Most link(CONCEPT_URBAN) building types require link(YIELD_STONE)icon(YIELD_STONE) to construct. Expect high demand for link(YIELD_STONE)icon(YIELD_STONE) as the game matures and you unlock new technologies.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_33</zType>
		<English>link(UNITTRAIT_RANGED) units are efficient in battle, often attacking an enemy without having to spend link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS) on movement.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_34</zType>
		<English>Cutting link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD) from link(VEGETATION_SCRUB) costs no link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS). If you move a link(UNIT_WORKER) through a link(VEGETATION_SCRUB) tile on its way to another destination, you can collect some free link(YIELD_WOOD)icon(YIELD_WOOD).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_35</zType>
		<English>link(UNIT_MILITIA) and link(UNIT_CONSCRIPT) units cannot be Promoted, but they are produced with link(YIELD_GROWTH)icon(YIELD_GROWTH) instead of link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING). Cities with high link(YIELD_GROWTH)icon(YIELD_GROWTH) output may be able to train them rapidly.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_36</zType>
		<English>link(UNITTRAIT_MOUNTED) units have the link(CONCEPT_ROUT) ability. When they slay an enemy unit, they occupy that unit's tile. Although they cannot move again, they can attack again if another target is adjacent to them.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_37</zType>
		<English>Consider spending link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING) to give Promotions to some of your units. Units who have engaged in combat and earned experience cost less link(YIELD_TRAINING)icon(YIELD_TRAINING) to promote.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_38</zType>
		<English>Tribes are not Nations. When at link(DIPLOMACY_WAR) with you, only their units near your units or territory pose a threat, unless you anger them enough for them to launch an Invasion.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_39</zType>
		<English>Coastal cities control less land than inland cities, but they tend to be less vulnerable to attack.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_40</zType>
		<English>Colder air forces clouds to drop their rain as they gain altitude to move over mountains. Most mountains have a lush band, where the rain falls, and a rain shadow on the opposite side, depending on regional wind patterns.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_41</zType>
		<English>Consider dealing with Events early in your turn. Some Event options require you to spend link(YIELD_ORDERS)icon(YIELD_ORDERS).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_42</zType>
		<English>A link(CONCEPT_ALLIANCE_TRIBE) allows you to found Cities peacefully next to your Ally's Sites.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_43</zType>
		<English>link(YIELD_CIVICS)icon(YIELD_CIVICS) stockpiles are capped at int(MAX_CIVICS). Above this value, they'll be converted to link(YIELD_SCIENCE)icon(YIELD_SCIENCE).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_44</zType>
		<English>Damaged link(UNIT_WORKER,2) take an extra turn to build improvements.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_45</zType>
		<English>[CTRL+Click] to automatically March a Unit to move past its Fatigue range.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_46</zType>
		<English>Hold [Z] to hide link(VEGETATION_TREES) and link(VEGETATION_SCRUB).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_47</zType>
		<English>Hold [X] to highlight Zones of Control.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_48</zType>
		<English>Hold [C] to highlight Tiles which enemy Units can target.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_49</zType>
		<English>Hold [V] to highlight Cities Connected to your Capital.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_50</zType>
		<English>Hold [B] to highlight Units which can still be used.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_51</zType>
		<English>Hold [N] to show what each of your Improvements produces.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_52</zType>
		<English>If your Leader is not able to complete an Ambition before death, it becomes a Legacy. Legacies count towards an Ambition Victory but are worth less link(CONCEPT_LEGITIMACY)icon(YIELD_LEGITIMACY).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_53</zType>
		<English>Barbarian level, chosen under Advanced Setup, affects the number of empty city sites near your capital.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_54</zType>
		<English>Non-coastal link(CONCEPT_URBAN) buildings must be adjacent to the City or to two other link(CONCEPT_URBAN) buildings.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_55</zType>
		<English>link(CONCEPT_URBAN) buildings on the coast need only be adjacent to one other link(CONCEPT_URBAN) building or the City.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_56</zType>
		<English>With a link(UNIT_WORKER) selected, hold [CTRL] and move the cursor over a tile to see what Improvements can be built there.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_57</zType>
		<English>link(UNIT_SCOUT,2) are invisible in link(VEGETATION_TREES).</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_58</zType>
		<English>Hold [SHIFT] or [MIDDLE-CLICK] to Freeze Tooltips.</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_59</zType>
		<English>Specialist are produced faster in higher-level improvements. (Poets take less time in an link(IMPROVEMENT_THEATER_2) than in an link(IMPROVEMENT_THEATER_1) - and even less time in a link(IMPROVEMENT_THEATER_3).)</English>
	</Entry>
	<Entry>
		<zType>TEXT_HINT_60</zType>
		<English>Hold down [SHIFT] when moving a Unit to assign a multi-turn destination. The Unit will move (to the edge of its Fatigue range) towards that Tile each turn.</English>
	</Entry>
</Root>
